<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: usb driver | Coding and Agile Processes]]></title>
  <link href="http://rendykstan.github.com/blog/categories/usb-driver/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rendykstan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-28T01:50:31+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://rendykstan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rendy Tan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Install Android USB driver on Windows 8]]></title>
    <link href="http://rendykstan.github.com/blog/2013/03/20/install-android-usb-driver-on-windows-8/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-20T23:29:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://rendykstan.github.com/blog/2013/03/20/install-android-usb-driver-on-windows-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With a broken power button on my Nexus S running Jelly Bean, the only way I can do a screen capture for the app we are releasing to the play store is to use Dalvik Debug Monitor Server (DDMS) tool in the Android SDK.</p>

<p>In the latest Android SDK, Google deprecated DDMS and introduced a new tool call Monitor as a replacement. Enabling "USB Debugging" on my Nexus S, it fails to show up on the device list.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>After some troubleshooting, we found out that the problem is because of a missing usb driver that I need to install on Windows 8. Here comes the problem. Windows is unable to search for a suitable driver online. The Samsung USB driver is only for Windows 7 and below. There are complex solutions that are more than a page long and many brick their phones trying.</p>

<p><strong>The solution:</strong></p>

<p><blockquote><p>If your device is one of the Android Developer Phones (ADP), a Nexus One, or a Nexus S, then you need the Google USB Driver, instead of an OEM driver. The Galaxy Nexus driver, however, is distributed by Samsung (listed as model SCH-I515).</p><footer><strong>developer.android.com</strong> <cite><a href='http://developer.android.com/tools/extras/oem-usb.html'>OEM USB Drivers</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p><strong>How to install the driver on Windows 8:</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Connect your Android-powered device to your computer's USB port.</li>
<li>Right-click on Computer from your desktop or Windows Explorer, and select Properties.</li>
<li>Select Device Manager in the left pane.</li>
<li>Locate and expand Other device in the list.</li>
<li>Right-click the device name (such as Nexus S) and select Update Driver Software. This will launch the Hardware Update Wizard.</li>
<li>Select Browse my computer for driver software and click Next.</li>
<li>Click Browse and locate the USB driver folder. (The Google USB Driver is located in \extras\google\usb_driver.)</li>
<li>Click Next to install the driver.</li>
</ol>


<p>After installing the driver, Nexus S will appear in the device list.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
